Geoffroy Herbin - Computer Vision - Assignment 1
switch between color and grayscale
Gaussian filters
Bilateral filters
Gaussian vs Bilateral filters
[Left] Gaussian = blurry
[Right] Bilateral = edge preserving
RGB colorspace
RGB colorspace grabbing using thresholding (tentative)
HSV colorspace
red = opening, green = dilatation, blue = closing
Calibration view - Sobel edge detection
Hough Transform
Parameters first chosen to isolate plant leaf
MinDist very small: multiple circles very close
Accumulator param2 lower: more (noisy) circles detected
(according to radius boundaries set)
Edge detection parameter param1 lower: more detections
Different set of parameters allow tuning towards specific target
Canny edge detection output shown
Object found using template matching technique ( CCOEFF_NORMED )
Brightest point has the highest probability of matching the template
Same scene, 3 yellow hockey balls
Let's track those balls on fire!
Goal Line Assistance
Simple hockey rule: ball must cross entirely the line to score